

Adil Zahoor Anjum
(Software Engineer) Android Developer

Phone: (+92) 3359981005

Email: adil.zahoor.anjum@gmail.com

Innovative Android Developer with 4 years of experience designing, developing, testing, and maintaining Android applications in the Healthcare & entertainment industries.

I'm a Software Engineer holding bachelor's degree, having **4** year's professional experience. I have completed many large scale android projects in my professional career and considered to be a skilled person in Android development (Native and Web Apps), XML, SQLite database, Firebase, Web services, Unit testing. I am eager to learn even more technologies to sharpen my skill set.

EXPERIENCE

Androweb IT Solutions:

june 2019- Present

Software Engineer (Android Developer)

Working as an Android developer at **Androweb IT Solutions**, where my primarily responsibilities to implement Android apps. **Key responsibilities include:**

- Development and architecture of android applications for clients and for play store as product
- Define and implement robust app architectures and complex user interfaces.
- Using Web Services and API's as well as perform unit testing.

Fun Prime Technology:

Jan 2018-May 2019

Software Engineer (Android Developer)

Working as an Android developer at The Fun Prime Technologies, Islamabad, where my primarily responsibilities to implement social apps. **Key responsibilities includes:**

- Development and architecture of android applications which were designed to maintain Teachers and Students.
- Used of Web Services and API's also used Web Rtc Cordova plug-in foraudio/video calling.
- Used of Web sockets for chatting.

CAST Technology:

Software Engineer (Android Developer) and Trainer

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018

Worked as an Android developer and trainer for students of COMSATS at Concept Academy of Science and Technology, where my primarily responsibilities to developed and maintained android applications.

Key responsibilities includes:

- Responsible to develop and maintain new applications (e.g. Native apps). Handled the tasks of updating new functionalities of existing applications.
- Developed applications and performed testing. Collaborated with designers, engineers, and product managers to build great experiences.

EDUCATION

CIIT (COMSATS Institute of Information Technology Islamabad):

2015 to 2017

Masters of Computer Science (MCS) CGPA: 3.13

I have completed my MCS degree from CIIT. During this degree, I have studies various courses, which provided me with a strong footing in the theoretical & Technical concepts of Software Engineering.

Final Year Project

Wedding Solutions (06/2016 - 01/2017)

A Android and Web based Application. An app to make the daily life functions easy, customer was able to book Hall, Catering, Photo Shoot and book Decorator online and also check the rates of different service providers. As well as Service providers got a lot of help with online booking and rating system

Development Languages: Java, J2ME (Android), Web services, XML, AJAX, PHP, HTML, CSS

SKILLS

- > Strong android application development, design, documentation and testing. Strong debugging experience with code written by other developers.
- Write elegant, self-documenting code, easy to read and adapt for other developers. Implementation of software design patterns.
- > Analytical skills.
- Unit testing

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND TOOLS

Programming Languages	Tools
Android development (Java) Database/Json/Room Web services Google Api's Databinding / Viewbinding Web Rtc for Audio/Video Calling Web sockets for chatting Familiar with phone Gap Cordova plugin	Android Studio Microsoft SQL server 2008/2014 Postman Github/TFS/Bitbucket Miro/Zeplin